Guide to the Seabury Mastick Papers 1891-2008
Pacific University Archives
Seabury Mastick Papers
1891-2008
MS.38
Pacific University, Archives http://www.pacificu.edu/library/services/archives/ 2043 College Way Forest Grove, OR, 97116 503-352-1405 archives@pacificu.edu
1.0 cubic foot 1 box
Seabury Cone Mastick was a legislator and banker in New York state who later married artist Kathrin Cawein. This collection contains correspondence, photographs, publications, a diploma from Oberlin College, and various legal documents.
Mastick, Seabury, 1871-1969
Biographical note
Seabury Cone Mastick was a legislator and banker in New York state who later married artist Kathrin Cawein. He was born in San Francisco, California on August 19, 1871 to William Henry Cone and Laura Jeanette Mastick. Left an orphan early in life, he was adopted by his mother’s brother and his wife, Seabury L. Mastick and Mary Wood Mastick. He attended Hopkins Academy in Oakland California before entering Oberlin College in 1887. While at Oberlin he met Agnes Eliza Warner, whom he married in 1896. After graduation he studied law at the University of California, Hastings School of Law receiving his Bachelor of Laws (LLB) in 1894. He also received a Masters Degree from Oberlin in 1894. He practiced law until 1917, specializing in patent litigation. In 1917 he became an officer in the United States Navy, rising to Lieutenant Commander before his retirement in 1920. He was awarded a silver star for inventing the high velocity star shell artillery ammunition. He later worked in chemical manufacturing after getting out of the navy. He had a career in politics from 1921 to 1935, serving on the New York State Assembly and as a New York Senator from 1923 to 1935. He worked in the banking industry from 1936 to 1958. Mr. and Mrs. Mastick had no children. Agnes Mastick died November 8th, 1963. The following year Seabury married artist Kathrin Cawein. Seabury died in Manchester, England on August 21, 1969.
Collection is open for research.
No accruals are expected.
Additional materials related to Seabury Mastick are in the papers of his second wife, Kathrin Cawein, which are also located in the Pacific University Archives. See the: Kathrin Cawein Collection, http://nwda-db.orbiscascade.org/findaid/ark:/80444/xv18951
This collection contains correspondence, photographs, publications, a diploma from Oberlin College, and various legal documents, all pertaining to Seabury Cone Mastick. Other materials include memorabilia from Oberlin College, and narratives of his travels. Additional materials pertain to Mastick's first wife, Agnes Warner Mastic, his second wife, Kathrin Cawein Mastick and his nephew, Fairfax Mastick Cone.
Cawein, Kathrin; Siegal, Alice
Colleges and universities
Correspondence
- Writings About Travels, 1913-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Contains narratives typed by Seabury detailing trips taken throughout his life. Destinations include Venice, Florence, and others.
- Biography Correspondence with Kathrin Mastic, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence between Kathrin Cawein Mastick and a representative from The National Cyclopedia of American Biography concerning inclusion of a piece on Seabury Mastic.
- Correspondence, 1948 to 2008 (Box 1, Folders 3-5)
  Contains letters and other material to and from Mr. and Mrs. Agnes Seabury Mastic.
- Correspondence with "A.A.F.J.", 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Original artwork is enclosed, along with a note to Seabury signed "A.A.F.J.".
- Fairfax Mastick Cone (nephew) Correspondence, 1942-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Contains correspondence and newspaper articles concerning Fairfax Cone Mastick, Seabury's nephew. He worked in advertising, heading up the firm Foote, Cone & Belding throughout most of its history.
- Death Certificate and Estate Correspondence, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Contains Seabury Mastic's death certificates, as well as letters and correspondence between Kathrin Cawein Mastick and various other individuals pertaining to various matters of Seabury Mastic's estate.
- Newsclippings and Printed Ephemera, 1963-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Contains a pamphlet titled "The Place of Healing in the Ministry of the Church" by Rev. George F. MacLeod, various news clippings, and a piece on Seabury's gift of a swimming pool to the town of Pleasantville.
- Legal Documents, 1938-1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Contains various legal documents, i.e. agreements and indentures, regarding Seabury Mastick Cone and Kathrin Cawein Mastic.
- Diplomas, 1952 to 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Contains Seabury's diplomas form Wagner Lutherin College and Pacific University, both written in latin.
- Horticulture Awards Agnes W. Mastick, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Includes awards for horticulture exhibits shown by Agnes Mastick for a show put on by the Horticultural Society of New York, as well as a pamphlet titled "1923 Mastick Dahlias", distributor M.G. Tyler.
- Miscellaneous Documents about Agnes W. Mastick, 1947-1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Includes a photo of Agnes taken in 1947 as well as a news clipping on Mr. and Mrs. Mastic's 60th wedding anniversary.
- Oberlin College Memorabilia, 1926-1976 (Box 1, Folders 14-15)
  Contains a variety of material having to do with Oberlin College at the time Seabury was teaching. Includes a photo album of commencement excercises, a Phi Delta Society pamphlet, and event programs.
- Oberlin Alumni Magazine, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  1969 edition containing a piece on Seabury written after his death.
- Photographs- Art Studio, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Contains photographs taken outside the Pacific University Art building showing movers unloading large barrels.
- Photographs, 1875 to 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Photographs of Seabury throughout his life, as well as some with Agnes Eliza Mastick and Kathrin Kawein.